<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.3">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://riddleverse.franciscogc.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://riddleverse.franciscogc.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2024-10-08T00:56:34+00:00</updated><id>https://riddleverse.franciscogc.com/feed.xml</id><title type="html">RiddleVerse</title><author><name>Francisco Cerqueira</name></author><entry><title type="html">Day 4: Echoes of Light</title><link href="https://riddleverse.franciscogc.com/stories/christmas2024/act1/echoes-of-light/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Day 4: Echoes of Light" /><published>2024-10-08T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-10-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://riddleverse.franciscogc.com/stories/christmas2024/act1/echoes-of-light</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://riddleverse.franciscogc.com/stories/christmas2024/act1/echoes-of-light/"><![CDATA[<p>You are on a grid with solar panels scattered across the field. The top-left corner contains the sunlight source focused through a magnifying glass, and the bottom-right corner is blocked by snow and ice, preventing your exit.</p>

<p>Due to your weakened state, you can only rotate two solar panels. Your task is to position them so that the sunlight reflects from panel to panel and reaches the snow-covered path at the bottom-right corner, melting the snow and clearing the way.</p>

<p>Here a representation of your location:</p>

<div><img class="challenge-img" src="/assets/img/stories/christmas2024/gridfield-with-panels.webp" /></div>

<p>You need to:</p>
<ul>
  <li>Rotate <strong>exactly two</strong> solar panels to direct the sunlight from the top-left corner to the bottom-right corner.</li>
  <li>The beam of light is casted with a <strong>45-degree</strong> angle, i.e. diagonally (as depicted by the arrow).</li>
  <li>The solar panels can only be rotated by a <strong>90-degree</strong> angle. Therefore, their orientation is either <strong>horizontal</strong> or <strong>vertical</strong>.</li>
  <li>The answer must contain the <strong>coordinates</strong> of the solar panels that need to be <strong>rotated</strong>.</li>
  <li>The answer must folow the format <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">x,y x,y</code>, where <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">x</code> indicates the column index and <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">y</code> indicates the row index. The top left corner position is <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">1,1</code>, while the bottom right position is <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">8,8</code>. The order of the coordinades is irrelevant.</li>
</ul>

<details>
 <summary>Hint 1</summary> 
 The light moves in straight lines and bounces at 90-degree angles from the panels. Consider which panels would redirect the ligth to a valid position.
</details>
<details>
 <summary>Hint 2</summary>
 Try starting from the end position and backtracking the beam path. There aren't so many options available...
</details>]]></content><author><name>Francisco Cerqueira</name></author><category term="christmas2024" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[You are on a grid with solar panels scattered across the field. The top-left corner contains the sunlight source focused through a magnifying glass, and the bottom-right corner is blocked by snow and ice, preventing your exit.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Day 3: Perilous Froststeps</title><link href="https://riddleverse.franciscogc.com/stories/christmas2024/act1/perilous-froststeps/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Day 3: Perilous Froststeps" /><published>2024-10-07T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-10-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://riddleverse.franciscogc.com/stories/christmas2024/act1/perilous-froststeps</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://riddleverse.franciscogc.com/stories/christmas2024/act1/perilous-froststeps/"><![CDATA[<p>As you stand before the magical staircase, the steps shimmer with ancient numbers. Some glow brightly, while others appear cracked and unstable, as if someone has tried and failed to ascend before. You notice that the steps marked <strong>2</strong>, <strong>3</strong>, <strong>5</strong>, <strong>7</strong>, and <strong>11</strong> appear safe, while others (up to the step number 11) show signs of wear and danger.</p>

<p>The Guardian’s cryptic words echo in your mind:</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>Step only on those numbers that follow the rhythm of the prime.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Given the fact that the staircase has 30 steps and the steps are inscribed with numbers ranging from 1 to 30, your task is to determine the correct sequence of safe steps based on this pattern.</p>

<p>Notice that:</p>
<ul>
  <li>The sequence values should be separated by commas (<code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">,</code>).</li>
  <li>The sequence should start with <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">2,3,5,7,11</code> and must be ordered from the smallest to the largest value.</li>
</ul>

<details>
 <summary>Hint 1</summary> 
 You notice that numbers like 2, 3, 5, 7, and 11 seem untouched and stable. There might be something special about these numbers.
</details>

<details>
 <summary>Hint 2</summary> 
 Look for numbers that can only be divided by 1 and themselves. These numbers seem to hold the key to safe passage.
</details>]]></content><author><name>Francisco Cerqueira</name></author><category term="christmas2024" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[As you stand before the magical staircase, the steps shimmer with ancient numbers. Some glow brightly, while others appear cracked and unstable, as if someone has tried and failed to ascend before. You notice that the steps marked 2, 3, 5, 7, and 11 appear safe, while others (up to the step number 11) show signs of wear and danger.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Day 2: The Rotating Labyrinth</title><link href="https://riddleverse.franciscogc.com/stories/christmas2024/act1/the-rotating-labyrinth/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Day 2: The Rotating Labyrinth" /><published>2024-10-06T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-10-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://riddleverse.franciscogc.com/stories/christmas2024/act1/the-rotating-labyrinth</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://riddleverse.franciscogc.com/stories/christmas2024/act1/the-rotating-labyrinth/"><![CDATA[<p>Knowing that, with each step you make, the maze rotates 90 degrees clockwise, you must determine the sequence of cardinal directions you must follow at each step in order to successfully reach the exit.</p>

<p>Here is the maze that you drew:</p>

<div><img class="challenge-img" src="/assets/img/stories/christmas2024/rotating-labyrinth-sketch.webp" /></div>

<p>Notice the following assumptions:</p>
<ul>
  <li>You already <strong>start inside</strong> the maze, at the initial tile <strong>(marked with red)</strong>, and you target position is <strong>outside</strong> the maze.</li>
  <li>The image is represented so that the <strong>North</strong> direction is pointing <strong>upwards</strong> and the <strong>South</strong> direction is pointing <strong>downwards</strong>.</li>
  <li>The sequence must <strong>only contain</strong> the letters <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">N</code>, <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">S</code>, <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">E</code>, and <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">W</code>. An example of an answer (obviously wrong) is <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">SENSW</code>.</li>
</ul>

<details>
 <summary>Hint 1</summary>
 The simplest (yet most time-consuming) approach is to determine the path <b>dynamically</b>, by rotating the maze each time you make a move. But there is a clever way to solve it...
</details>

<details>
 <summary>Hint 2</summary>
 The second approach consists in determining the path <b>statically</b>, by solving the path while ignoring the rotations. After that, you only need to rotate each step according to its position in the sequence. For example, the second step should be rotated by 90 degrees, the third by 180 degrees, and so on.
</details>]]></content><author><name>Francisco Cerqueira</name></author><category term="christmas2024" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Knowing that, with each step you make, the maze rotates 90 degrees clockwise, you must determine the sequence of cardinal directions you must follow at each step in order to successfully reach the exit.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Day 1: The Icy Threshold</title><link href="https://riddleverse.franciscogc.com/stories/christmas2024/act1/the-icy-threshold/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Day 1: The Icy Threshold" /><published>2024-10-05T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-10-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://riddleverse.franciscogc.com/stories/christmas2024/act1/the-icy-threshold</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://riddleverse.franciscogc.com/stories/christmas2024/act1/the-icy-threshold/"><![CDATA[<p>The riddle etched into the gates reads:</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>I am not alive, but I grow; I don’t have lungs, but I need air; I don’t have a mouth, but I can drown. What am I?</p>
</blockquote>

<details>
 <summary>Hint 1</summary>
 "I thrive on fuel but vanish in water."
</details>

<details>
 <summary>Hint 2</summary>
 "I'm used to warm homes and light the way in darkness."
</details>]]></content><author><name>Francisco Cerqueira</name></author><category term="christmas2024" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[The riddle etched into the gates reads:]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Prologue</title><link href="https://riddleverse.franciscogc.com/stories/christmas2024/act1/prologue/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Prologue" /><published>2024-10-04T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-10-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://riddleverse.franciscogc.com/stories/christmas2024/act1/act-1-prologue</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://riddleverse.franciscogc.com/stories/christmas2024/act1/prologue/"><![CDATA[<p><br /></p>

<p>In a hidden realm parallel to our world, the Christmas Spirit is kept alive by three powerful artifacts: the Ember of Warmth, the Crystal of Joy, and the Veil of Wonder. Each artifact rests under the protection of legendary Guardians. Every century, these artifacts must be reawakened to renew the magic of Christmas. But this year, something has gone terribly wrong.</p>

<p><br /></p>

<p>A malevolent force has swept through the Christmas Realm, imprisoning the Guardians and securing the artifacts. Without the artifacts, the magic of Christmas will fade, and with it, the warmth, joy, and wonder cherished by people across the world.</p>

<p><br /></p>

<p>Your quest begins at the coldest point of this calamity—the Ember of Warmth. Once the heart of the Christmas Realm’s light and love, it now lies dormant, hidden deep within the Vault of the Hearth. The Guardian of the Hearth, bound in icy chains, can no longer protect it. The once vibrant lands are now veiled in a creeping chill, and the Ember’s glow has dimmed, casting shadows where warmth used to reign.</p>

<p><br /></p>

<p>To restore balance and save Christmas, you must embark on a perilous journey into the frozen wilderness. The Ember of Warmth must be reignited, but the path is treacherous, filled with ancient puzzles and guarded secrets. The fate of the Christmas Realm, and the very spirit of Christmas, rests in your hands.</p>

<p><br /></p>

<p>Good luck, adventurer!</p>]]></content><author><name>Francisco Cerqueira</name></author><category term="christmas2024" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry></feed>